Finding Aid for Taubman Medical Libray records, 1966-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Taubman Medical Libray records 1966-1980
Taubman Medical Libray
2 linear feet
87330 Bimu C430 2
Records, 1966-1980, related to the planning and construction of the Taubman Medical Library, which is located in the University of Michigan's Medical Center area and serves the University's Medical and Health Information communities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection (Donor Number 6832 ) was acquired by the Bentley Library in October 1982.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Taubman Medical Library, built between 1978 and 1980, is located in the University of Michigan's Medical Center area and serves the University's Medical and Health Information communities.
The collection consists of the library's Planning Phase (1966-1977) and Construction Phase (1978-1980). The papers concerning the planning phase include building programs, designs, architectural programs, questionnaires, proposals, consultant reports, and notes and correspondence. The construction phase files contain the minutes of the building construction meetings and the library-moving project.
Subjects:
Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; Taubman Medical Library.
- Planning Phase, 1966-1979
  - 1965-1973
    - Building Program for the Proposed Health Sciences Information Center at the University of Michigan, 1965-1967, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Design for a University Health Services Information Center, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Health Sciences Information Center Library and Medlars Questionnaires, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Medical Center Library, by David K. Maxfield, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Notes and Correspondence, 1965-1973, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1974-1979
    - Grant Request Proposal, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Additional Information for Grant, 1974 (Box 1)
    - The Rice Proposal, 1974 (Box 1)
    - First Proposal, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Consultants and Aftermath, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Second Draft and Aftermath, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Final Accepted Proposal, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Notes and Correspondence, 1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Program for the Library Portion of the Medical Center Library and Learning Resource Center, 1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Prospectus for a Medical Library "The Medical Center Library and the Learning Resource Center," 1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Report to the Medical Center Library and Learning Resource Center Building Committee User Survey, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Architectural Programs, 1975-1976, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Combined Program Draft JUG/NSF, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Specifications for the University of Michigan Medical Center Library and Learning Resource Center
      - Job 7602, 1976, one volume (Box 2)
      - Addendum to 7602, 1976 (Box 2)
      - Schematic Planning, 1976 (Box 2)
      - Library Shelving, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Notes and Correspondence, 1975-1977, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Medical Center Library and Learning Resource Center Building Program, 1976 (Box 2)
- Construction Phase 1978-1980
  - Building Construction Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - Moving Project, 1980 (Box 2)